redtedart.com 2019-05-07

# Cookies, Privacy Policies & Disclosure - Red Ted Art

## **Privacy Policy for Red Ted Art Ltd**

The privacy of visitors to www.redtedart.com is important to us.

At Red Ted Art Ltd, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit www.redtedart.com, and how we safeguard your information. **We never sell your personal information to third parties.**

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, www.redtedart.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Newsletters and Data Protection**

Red Ted Art Limited will collect your name and email address for the purpose of regular email/ newsletter communication. In general you will receive 1-3 emails per week, sharing with you  the latest craft ideas, as well as occassional product recommendations. Your email data will NEVER be supplied to third parties and will be held on the [Mailerlite ](https://www.mailerlite.com/)servers.

The email address and any additional information supplied (e.g. name) will be held on the Mailerlite server for as long as you wish to receive newsletters from Red Ted Art Ltd. Should you wish to discontinue receiving newsletters, please hit unsubscribe link on bottom of the newsletters or email info (at) redtedart (dot) com and we can do the unsubscription for you.

Should you be unhappy about any way your data has been handled, you can make a complaint to the [ICO](https://ico.org.uk/) at any time.

## Amazon Affiliate links

You will notice that I frequently add product links to blog post – to make it easier to get hold of certain items needed to make a craft. This links will usually be Amazon Affiliate links.

As an Amazon Associate I earn from qualifying purchases.

The earnings go towards the up keep and running of this blog!

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Red Ted Ary uses cookies that

  * Are part of our commenting system so that you don’t have to always enter you details
  * Collect data as part of Google Analytics so that we can see who has visited our website

We use third party advertisements on www.redtedart.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in your browser. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

## DoubleClick DART cookies

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on  Red Ted Art.
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to Red Ted Art and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html or [click through to opt out](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:

  * Google Adsense
  * [Adthrive](https://www.adthrive.com/) Advertising

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on Red Ted Art send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.Red Ted Art has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Red Ted Art’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

## Disclosure

  * This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation.
  * The compensation received will never influence the content, topics or posts made in this blog. All advertising is in the form of advertisements generated by a third party ad network. Those advertisements will be identified as paid advertisements.
  * The owner of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.
  * This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

  * To get your own policy, go to http://www.disclosurepolicy.org
  * This policy is valid from 07 July 2011

### Affiliate Links

Note: on occasion Red Ted Art will share an affiliate link with you – usually to Amazon books or craft supplies, that have been used on Red Ted Art. On those occasions should you purchase the item through the affiliate link, I will receive a small percentage of the sale, which helps cover running costs of this site.
